[{"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888f", "question": "Who is Othello's wife?", "answer": "Desdemona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd58ae347d002c297e4b7", "question": "What year did James Fenimore Cooper publish the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\"?", "answer": "1826", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a096", "question": "Which film features the line, \"I could have been a contender\"?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3234babf195a31e15d73a8", "question": "Which chemical element gets its name from the Greek for \"Violet-colored\"?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339977", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny has a master's degree in what field?", "answer": "Nuclear Physics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a551be3e1c6f9840ba318f", "question": "Corfu is part of which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabb", "question": "Which part of the body suffers from Microphthalmia?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b107", "question": "How many Americans from the US Embassy in Iran were taken hostage in November, 1979?", "answer": "63", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a570", "question": "What US city is famous for its French Quarter?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f89", "question": "Who is the author of the book \"The Life-changing Magic of Tidying Up\"?", "answer": "Marie Kondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc4dd6ce05a3942286f38", "question": "What is the name of the fishing boat that is featured in the film \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "Andrea Gail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20ff931a458464a93c43a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff519baff04d658268c9302", "question": "What was Joan of Arc charged with that led to her execution?", "answer": "Heresy -- Her most serious crime was her rejection of church authority in favor of direct inspiration from God.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66638a5bfecdd737e0867", "question": "What color is second from the top in a rainbow?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfe", "question": "What billionaire piloted the first hot-air balloon ever to cross the Atlantic?", "answer": "Richard Branson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d117014fea7fe947a22276", "question": "Mickey Mouse is known as what in Italy?", "answer": "Topolino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b941", "question": "What 4 tournaments make up golf's Grand Slam for men?", "answer": "Masters, PGA, U.S. & British Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa40f5c73aa70ea0b70b0d", "question": "What was the first country to make broadband internet access a legal right?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd9487e83c707845b2179", "question": "Who was the original \"Bozo the Clown\"?", "answer": "Vance \"Pinto\" Colvig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c497", "question": "Which French philosopher said \"Cogito Ergo Sum\"?", "answer": "Rene Descartes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e2", "question": "What photojournalist's work made the first cover of \"Life\" magazine?", "answer": "Margaret Bourke-White", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b824", "question": "What do Mc and Mac mean when used in surnames?", "answer": "Son of", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f0", "question": "What is the fear of heredity known as?", "answer": "Patroiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b048", "question": "In what year did Lewis & Clark depart St. Louis to begin their expedition to the west?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f46bcee580c7f8fd1e58", "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b234", "question": "What athlete was born in West Baden, Indiana, in December 1956?", "answer": "Larry Bird", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2139131a458464a93c450", "question": "In 2012, students at MIT hacked the lighting system of an entire building to play which game?", "answer": "Tetris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66029a5bfecdd737e0831", "question": "What percentage of Americans believe in Astrology", "answer": "26", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c81afbde8045e48466cf", "question": "What are the tiny air sacs in the lungs called?", "answer": "Alveoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a508", "question": "The city of Machu Picchu is located in which country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4da", "question": "Which is larger, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a877", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Nevsky Prospekt\"?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7dc8ff048f679a45abfe", "question": "Androphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Men", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc60", "question": "What material is denim made from?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ffaa83a3a814d89068c5d", "question": "In the 1988 film \"Twins\", what were the character names of Arnold Schwarzenneger and Danny De Vito?", "answer": "Julius and Vincent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56e", "question": "What is the atomic number of the chemical element gold?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee0", "question": "What literary villain died during a struggle at Reichenbach Falls?", "answer": "Professor Moriarty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8b", "question": "What former World Heavyweight Champion boxer was nicknamed \"The Brown Bomber\"?", "answer": "Joe Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f8", "question": "Who was the second Toronto Blue Jay player to lead the American league in home runs?", "answer": "Fred McGriff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a068", "question": "What group was Ringo Starr with before the Beatles?", "answer": "Rory Storm and the Hurricanes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb3", "question": "Which US gangster described himself as a used furniture dealer on his business card?", "answer": "Al Capone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c8", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4a5b49076251badbeab4", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8d5cec223966ae8f8852", "question": "What is the name of the leader of the gang that often assaulted Andy in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Bogs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb4", "question": "Which famous number was dreaded by people in Orwell\u2019s 1984?", "answer": "101", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338edb", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Don Quixote?", "answer": "Rocinante", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d66", "question": "Who played the role of TV's D. J. Tanner?", "answer": "Candace Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339274", "question": "What is the fairy tale equivalent of Augustus in the show \"Once Upon A Time\"?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dfa7f4f3bc4a292f862d", "question": "Who composed the famous Christmas song \"Jingle Bells\"?", "answer": "American composer James Lord Pierpont composed \"Jingle Bells\" in 1875 for Thanksgiving.  It later became a popular Christmas song.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a44020565ad31a57c7ba", "question": "The first U.S. transcontinental airmail service connected New York with which city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601219cf63c99d48cd169afb", "question": "What is someone who shoes horses?", "answer": "A farrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339607", "question": "Who played the role of the fugitive in the 1993 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Harrison Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d077ab870e6f05ba600866", "question": "Which private eye character did the author Raymond Chandler create?", "answer": "Philip Marlowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d9b02596a59cbdfbd3c9", "question": "What was the first crime Billy the Kid was arrested for?", "answer": "Stealing clothes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe775edeec85e375820b313", "question": "How many states does Mexico have?", "answer": "31", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d8", "question": "Princeton University is located in which state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071cd83745b36be73039d0", "question": "Who worked as the lead Soviet rocket engineer during the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union?", "answer": "Sergei Korolev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008c40cf842fa4c4ba969e", "question": "With which horror film series would you associate the character Leatherface?", "answer": "Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4a", "question": "In the movie \"The Matrix\", what colored pill does Neo take?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d1a4bb53d1af65886503", "question": "Who wrote the 1958 book \"Journey to Christmas\"?", "answer": "B. J. Chute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec3", "question": "Who created the New Model Army?", "answer": "Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7bf", "question": "In pool, what color is the 4-ball?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51c", "question": "By what name is the island of Rapa Nui better known?", "answer": "Easter Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada6", "question": "The \"Italian Plague of 1629-31\" is also referred to as by what other name?", "answer": "Great Plague of Milan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef7", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Roy Hobbs?", "answer": "The Natural", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00d", "question": "What was the real first name of David Soul's \"Hutch\" on \"Starsky and Hutch\"?", "answer": "Ken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c28", "question": "Who wrote \"Little House in the Big Woods\"?", "answer": "Laura Ingalls Wilder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f8", "question": "Which character did Raquel Welch play in the 1966 science fiction film \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Cora", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4bc", "question": "When did the Comoros gain its independence from France?", "answer": "July 6, 1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76f3eeec85e375820b2e5", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6e", "question": "Oak trees are part of which genus?", "answer": "Quercus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4d", "question": "In 1819, the US purchased Florida from what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8a", "question": "Liquid Paper was invented by Bette Graham, the mother of which of the Monkees?", "answer": "Mike Nesmith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc2f4ec223966ae8f8879", "question": "Which major sports league does not let its players to wear the number 0?", "answer": "MLS", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa8820565ad31a57c81a", "question": "In which German city did Joseph Stalin, Winston Churchill and President Franklin D Roosevelt meet in 1945?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaaa", "question": "What is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cde15e347d002c297e4f8", "question": "Who wrote the classic science fiction novel \"Helliconia Winter\"?", "answer": "Brian W. Aldiss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48b", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd6", "question": "What actress had the word \"Miss\" listed before her first name in the credits of \"The Waltons\"?", "answer": "Michael Learned", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4bd", "question": "What year did the Seychelles gain their independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1976", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2155b31a458464a93c45e", "question": "Which dog breed yodels rather than barks?", "answer": "Basenjis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c71", "question": "Who wrote the 1976 novel \"Interview with the Vampire\"?", "answer": "Ann Rice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bc92fb6c85e9e634ff5e", "question": "Majorca is the largest of which island group?", "answer": "Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a499", "question": "What is the longest river in the world?", "answer": "Nile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d2f6bb53d1af6588650e", "question": "Who played the lead role in the 1983 film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff256c931a458464a93c461", "question": "What patented structure does Apple feature in its stores?", "answer": "Glass staircase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389be", "question": "What country provides the setting for \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Siam (Thailand)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339172", "question": "Mark Hamill was a voice actor for which popular early 90's superhero cartoon?", "answer": "Batman: The Animated Series", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afc", "question": "Which character killed Uncle Tom?", "answer": "Simon Legree", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f4", "question": "Chevrolet sold a souped-up version of what car as the \"Z24\"?", "answer": "The Cavalier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6660ea5bfecdd737e0864", "question": "How many breaths does an average human take each day?", "answer": "23,040", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d3", "question": "What is the Latin name for the atmospheric glow also called the \"southern lights\"?", "answer": "Aurora australis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe640a8ae7e414034b5aea4", "question": "Which countries participated in the Lobster War?", "answer": "France and Brazil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb98", "question": "What athletic apparel company took its name from the Greek goddess of Victory?", "answer": "Nike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95b05555722f97b22684dc", "question": "Who was the Hogwarts' headmaster right before Dumbledore?", "answer": "Armando Dippet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918f", "question": "What time are all the clocks stuck on in the movie, \"Pulp Fiction\"?", "answer": "4:20", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b7e0364247bf200fb878", "question": "Which Canadian city's nickname is \"Bytown\"?", "answer": "Ottawa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbae7ab0738315b1fb74e26", "question": "What mathematician published \"Elements\" and influenced the study of modern geometry?", "answer": "Euclid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe378b80ada16518afdc053", "question": "Which Christmas tune was the first song performed in space?", "answer": "\"Jingle Bells\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b434", "question": "How long did the Mau Mau Uprising last?", "answer": "8 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049be6cf93664eb10486a2", "question": "The \"Eisner Award\" is named after which influential cartoonist and writer?", "answer": "Will Eisner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeba", "question": "Who was the French President from 1969 until his death in 1974?", "answer": "Georges Pompideau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6c", "question": "What is the name of the sequel to the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Staying Alive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a21a", "question": "Craig Phillips was the first winner of which TV reality show?", "answer": "UK's \"Big Brother\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18a", "question": "Which famous city bridge is known locally as \"The Coathanger\"?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour Bridge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be2", "question": "What year did Elvis die in?", "answer": "1977", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04e", "question": "Which U.S. President signed the National Aeronautics and Space Act establishing NASA?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf4", "question": "What disorder did Muhammad Ali develop after retiring from boxing?", "answer": "Parkinson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a120", "question": "Which year did John Schlesinger receive an Academy Award for directing \"Midnight Cowboy\"?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934c", "question": "What movie star was considered for the role of Dad in the TV show \"The Brady Bunch\"?", "answer": "Gene Hackman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac31", "question": "What was the first railroad to cross the US?", "answer": "The Union Pacific", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be45", "question": "What is the name of Twitter's blue bird mascot?", "answer": "Larry the Bird", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1df", "question": "The single \"Up Where We Belong\" is taken from which film?", "answer": "An Officer and a Gentleman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4dd0206d333868d34d6fe", "question": "What documents were responsible for establishing the 17th Parallel as the line that separated Vietnam during the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Geneva Accords", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96acf23c87fd04dd15e15", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last person to go directly from Vice President to President of the United States?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c53", "question": "Who was the host of \"The Tonight Show\" from 1954 to 1957?", "answer": "Steve Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac77", "question": "When was the modern tire first introduced to the market?", "answer": "1887", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d2", "question": "Who played the role of C.K. Dexter-Haven in the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Bing Crosby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80433de59ea584496fea3", "question": "Who wrote the 1956 novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Dodie Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b84ffb6c85e9e634ff4e", "question": "What nationality is golfer Paul Azinger?", "answer": "American", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b378", "question": "What was the nationality of Franz Liszt?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c558", "question": "What is the common name for \"graphospasm\"?", "answer": "Writer's cramp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c578", "question": "What nearby galaxy is name for a mythological princess?", "answer": "Andromeda Galaxy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972e", "question": "How many husbands did Elizabeth Taylor have?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37a", "question": "Which city was the first ever to host the Olympic Games twice?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5922002ba4edfd43a087add7", "question": "A \"Panatela\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Cigar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d2", "question": "What guitar player was the last act to perform at the original Woodstock in 1969?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc6", "question": "Who provoked controversy with the phone-sex conversation on her 1997 album \"The Velvet Rope\"?", "answer": "Janet Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a686", "question": "Which three states share a border with Michigan?", "answer": "Indiana, Ohio and Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d5", "question": "What musical is set at Rydell High?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339097", "question": "In Greek mythology, Hera was the goddess of what?", "answer": "Women and marriage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523e56736d4be723796b4e", "question": "In what decade did Toronto surpass Montreal as the most populous city in Canada?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9e", "question": "Bill Gates dropped out of which of educational institution?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a53b", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Motor City\"?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78e", "question": "What is a shuriken?", "answer": "A throwing star", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0662596a59cbdfbd37b", "question": "Who said, \"Whenever I hear anyone arguing for slavery, I feel a strong impulse to see it tried on him personally\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f1781e4b8195c09b948d5c2", "question": "Which abolitionist wrote the newspapers called \"The Liberator\"?", "answer": "William Lloyd Garrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395aa", "question": "Who played Elliot Ness in the 1987 movie \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba69", "question": "In what year was Gettysburg National Military Park founded?", "answer": "1895", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e0", "question": "\"Mork & Mindy\" was a spin-off of what TV show?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5956425b803c1f1ebcc4a02c", "question": "Tim McGraw and Faith Hill won the Academy of Country Music\u2019s very first Vocal Event trophy in 1997 for what song?", "answer": "\"It\u2019s Your Love\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7351ceec85e375820b244", "question": "Who was Dwight D. Eisenhower's vice president?", "answer": "Richard M. Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b071", "question": "Which former First Lady co\u00adwrote the Declaration of Human Rights which was adopted by the United Nations?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52db81bf59ab7d2e3810d", "question": "What is the best-selling ice-cream flavor in the US?", "answer": "Vanilla", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a9b520565ad31a57c809", "question": "Who was President George Washington's Secretary of War?", "answer": "Henry Knox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc1100469bb8041d07a072", "question": "What is the correct plural of Keeshond?", "answer": "Keeshonden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc7", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Sancho Panza?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339355", "question": "What year did \"The Captain Kangaroo Show\" first air?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85a", "question": "Which US state is the third largest state by land area?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338962", "question": "What is the first name of Agatha Christie's sleuth Miss Marple?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a1", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc17", "question": "What organization was formed to replace \"The League of Nations\"?", "answer": "United Nations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c6d70775fa611bce67d3", "question": "What popular 1990s toy was banned from the U.S. National Security Agency's HQ?", "answer": "Furby -- It had a recording and repeating function. It could be a problem in a place full of confidential material.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ea", "question": "How much money do you start a game of standard \"Monopoly\" with?", "answer": "$1500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd9", "question": "What did Levi Strauss invent in 1872?", "answer": "Blue jeans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66959a5bfecdd737e087a", "question": "Who was the last king of Troy in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Priam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37d", "question": "What is the capital of Peru?", "answer": "Lima", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d3", "question": "Which company introduced Comet cleanser back in 1956?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99b8221a8909e5c332d2c", "question": "When was the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" released?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8de5ec223966ae8f8859", "question": "What character does Will Ferrell play in the movie \"Anchorman\"?", "answer": "Ron Burgundy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded232ea2747c8aff16d3b", "question": "At which motor racing circuit did Ayrton Senna have a fatal accident?", "answer": "Imola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba51", "question": "What was the denomination of the first American adhesive stamp?", "answer": "Five cents", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b906364247bf200fb886", "question": "Aulophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Flutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abe", "question": "What was Drew Barrymore's character\u2019s name in \"E.T.: The Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Gertie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945a", "question": "Who does Eddie Murphy trade places with in the 1983 movie \"Trading Places\"?", "answer": "Dan Aykroyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bd05b7e40191c55fd523fb2", "question": "What horror game created more fear of animatronics?", "answer": "Five Nights At Freddy's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6706e52a821ff76ae8b21", "question": "What is a cartomancer?", "answer": "A fortune teller who uses cards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beca", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the name of the electronics company, JVC?", "answer": "Japan's Victor Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d3", "question": "The card game Patience is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec5", "question": "What two future Munsters costarred in the TV show \"Car 54, Where Are You\"?", "answer": "Fred Gwynne and Al Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c902", "question": "What is the fear of nudity known as?", "answer": "Gymnophobia or Nudophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe77025eec85e375820b2f6", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most populous island?", "answer": "Java, Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c5a40775fa611bce67ca", "question": "The spice paprika is made from what?", "answer": "Sweet pepper pods -- Paprika is made from ground sweet pepper pods that are dried and powdered.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febbcc97e83c707845b2151", "question": "Popular actress Gabrielle Union married which NBA player in 2014?", "answer": "Dwayne Wade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb07", "question": "Canonized in 1933, what famous nun is the patron saint of the French pilgrimage town of Lourdes?", "answer": "St. Bernadette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2f", "question": "What original animal mascot for Trix cereal was replaced by a rabbit in 1967?", "answer": "Flamingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa38e9c73aa70ea0b70ad6", "question": "How many U.S. states are named after a President?", "answer": "One (Washington is named after George Washington, the first U.S. president.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef93af6ce05a3942286e91", "question": "Andy Dufresne was particularly skilled and knowledgeable in what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Finance and Taxation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a048", "question": "In what year was the hit game \"Minecraft\" released?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c7", "question": "What is the Latin name for a guinea pig?", "answer": "Caviaprocellus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c36ad815febcc896f9269", "question": "Who runs the \"Leftorium\"?", "answer": "Ned Flanders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e184fe83fe1f2a824b95", "question": "What happened at Dunkirk in May 1940?", "answer": "British forces retreated across the English Channel.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb73dbc5e259d7869087335", "question": "During the Kentucky Derby races, what fashion event is known as part southern tradition and part spectacle?", "answer": "The Hat Parade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c934877e98cb977789f1", "question": "What is Africa's oldest continuous democracy?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa6296ce05a3942286ecc", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Frances McDormand plays the pregnant police chief of what town?", "answer": "Bernard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad24", "question": "How did the ancient Irish mark their land?", "answer": "The rock they cleared was the land they had.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc13", "question": "What year did designer Manolo Blahnik open his first namesakes store in Hong Kong?", "answer": "1991", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339992", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Cosby Show\" were made?", "answer": "197", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddeb477980686f722d180", "question": "Which Empire is typically associated with the invention of the early fork?", "answer": "Roman Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b491249076251badbeaab", "question": "America\u2019s first multimillionaire, John Jacob Astor, made his fortune in what?", "answer": "A fur trade monopoly -- He also made money smuggling opium to China and investing in real estate in and around New York City.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c901", "question": "What word, beginning with M, is the unit measurement for the brightness of stars?", "answer": "Magnitude", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339576", "question": "What Christmas single has the biggest sales of all time?", "answer": "White Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b599", "question": "Which artist's song was the 10 billionth iTunes download?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597ddba577980686f722d177", "question": "What year was the first patent for a pencil sharpener applied for?", "answer": "1828", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce2", "question": "At what US city did Bugs Bunny traditionally lament taking a left \"toin\"?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea5", "question": "What famous World War II general went into battle wearing two ivory-handled revolvers on his hips?", "answer": "General George Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b556", "question": "What is Hershey's most popular product?", "answer": "Reeses Peanut Butter Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a217", "question": "Who was the first winner of the British version of the TV reality show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d78", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Pure Woman, Faithfully Presented\"?", "answer": "Tess of the D'Urbervilles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee7", "question": "Who was British Prime Minister on V-J day?", "answer": "Clement Attlee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339582", "question": "What movie takes place on February 2nd again and again?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc2", "question": "Whom did Vietnam gain independence from in 1954?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5b", "question": "What Broadway great's daughter wrote the book \"Freaky Friday\"?", "answer": "Richard Rodgers'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc1", "question": "What is a gricer interested in?", "answer": "Trains", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d116054fea7fe947a2226c", "question": "What group of natural pigments affects the color of the hair and skin?", "answer": "Melanin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339652", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1954 movie \"Them!\"?", "answer": "Ants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925c", "question": "What French detective features in the \"Pink Panther\" movies?", "answer": "Jacques Clouseau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b136", "question": "Abraham Zapruder gained fame for filming what important event in US history?", "answer": "JFK assassination", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad15", "question": "Who is the founder of Carthage?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b9", "question": "Texas City is located at the mouth of what bay?", "answer": "Galveston Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8fc0301dd7bf43be5e857", "question": "The name \"Sahara\" is derived from the Arabic word for what?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998d", "question": "What was the name of the blonde girl in the cartoon show \"Scooby-Doo\"?", "answer": "Daphne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb33cde368446ca7bd6848", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", what is the name of the shrew?", "answer": "Katherina", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded1f4ea2747c8aff16d38", "question": "Laliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Speaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20a", "question": "Who won Best Supporting Actress for her role in the 1980's film \"Melvin and Howard\"?", "answer": "Mary Steenburgen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb2af65ff7d326b622a77", "question": "Mycophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecdd29ec223966ae8f8900", "question": "What band is the film \"Bohemian Rhapsody\" about?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f5", "question": "Who was famous for saying: \"All you need to fly are lovely things and fairy dust\"?", "answer": "Peter Pan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6b", "question": "Which doctor did Hugh Lofting write a series of books about?", "answer": "Dr. Dolittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ed", "question": "Shakespeare mentioned his wife only once in his will, making her the odd bequest of his \"second best\" what?", "answer": "Bed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7353deec85e375820b247", "question": "Who said, \"I am prepared to meet my Maker. Whether my Maker is prepared for the ordeal of meeting me is another matter.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a9a120565ad31a57c808", "question": "Who issued the \"Emancipation Proclamation\"?", "answer": "President Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa7", "question": "A plague is a group of what insect?", "answer": "Locust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0da", "question": "Which Latin word is used to express the meaning \"word for word\"?", "answer": "Verbatim", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e1", "question": "What do SETI programs search for?", "answer": "Extraterrestrial Intelligence", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e78906d333868d34d73f", "question": "Who was known as the \"Mad Monarch\"?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ef0701dd7bf43be5e7f0", "question": "What is the last name of Barbie's boyfriend, Ken?", "answer": "Carson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe772e2eec85e375820b302", "question": "Which mountain is depicted in Toblerone chocolate bars' logo?", "answer": "The Matterhorn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990af76b72eedf883a8c707", "question": "Which US state was nicknamed \"Old Dominion\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15c", "question": "At which sport was Hungarian Victor Barna World Champion 5 times?", "answer": "Table Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d0776d870e6f05ba600863", "question": "What was astronaut Edwin Eugene Aldrin Jr.'s nickname?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21e", "question": "What city was Indira Gandhi killed in?", "answer": "New Delhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1de", "question": "Which US president lived in Mount Vernon?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c583", "question": "What is Philo T. Farnsworth credited with for inventing?", "answer": "Television", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d1", "question": "In 2004, Norodom Sihanouk renounced the throne of what Asian country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefa", "question": "In what country was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c864", "question": "What pitcher lent his name to ulnar collateral ligament reconstruction?", "answer": "Tommy John", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabe", "question": "On the Mohs scale, what is the softest mineral?", "answer": "Talc", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f4", "question": "What country borders both of the world's only two nations with square flags?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33e", "question": "What musical parodist sang the Halloween song \"Nature Trail to Hell\"?", "answer": "Weird Al Yankovic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc18c6ce05a3942286f12", "question": "Which band sang in 1999 the smash hit \"Blue (Da Ba Dee)\"?", "answer": "Eiffel 65", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338913", "question": "What must be held by anyone wishing to speak during meetings in the book \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "Conch shell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c5", "question": "In 1643 Evangalista Torichelli invented the first what?", "answer": "Barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f4c", "question": "On what TV show did Hillary Clinton describe \"a vast right-wing conspiracy\" in 1998?", "answer": "The Today Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3cb4c73aa70ea0b70aee", "question": "Which capital name means \"City of Joy?\"", "answer": "Bucharest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339114", "question": "What year was H. G. Wells' \"The Inivisible Man\" serialized by Pearson's Weekly?", "answer": "1897", "category": "arts"}]